<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[A GitHub Pages Blog using Gatsby, covering personal projects relating to Software Development, DevOps, and Cloud Infrastructure.]]></description><link>https://ben-james-dodwell.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 09:10:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The Cloud Resume Challenge]]></title><description><![CDATA[At some point last year, I stumbled upon The Cloud Resume Challenge and saved the link to revisit when I had the chance. To summarise, the…]]></description><link>https://ben-james-dodwell.github.io/the-cloud-resume-challenge/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ben-james-dodwell.github.io/the-cloud-resume-challenge/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 08:12:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;At some point last year, I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudresumechallenge.dev/&quot;&gt;The Cloud Resume Challenge&lt;/a&gt; and saved the link to revisit when I had the chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarise, the challenge has you create your resume (or curriculum vitae) as a web page using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Then, using DevOps methodologies and technologies, deploy the resume to a cloud service provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several aspects of the challenge that appeal to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, while I wouldn&apos;t consider myself to be a talented web designer due to shortage of artistic ability, I feel that I&apos;ve attained a basic competence from some of my personal projects over the past few years. I like the control over layout and styling that HTML and CSS provides. Being able to use responsive web design techniques seems beneficial, for example, providing a better user experience for anyone that views the resume on a mobile device. Also, having this kind of document under source control seems like it could be useful to at least view change history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I would love to learn more about cloud engineering and DevOps. I have some exposure from my previous and current employment, but more can only help. The Cloud Resume Challenge provides a few variants, covering different cloud service providers or advanced technologies; I currently have more experience with Microsoft Azure but would like to spend more time with AWS so I will follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudresumechallenge.dev/docs/the-challenge/aws/&quot;&gt;The Cloud Resume Challenge - AWS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the obvious benefit to this challenge is the outcome. Having a resume available online which is easy to share and easy to maintain should help with career opportunities. The learning and experience from the project can hopefully be used throughout my career, and it also makes a great talking point and provides examples to be used in future interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let&apos;s begin.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Blog for GitHub Pages]]></title><description><![CDATA[I have a personal project that I've wanted to start for a while, and felt that it could be beneficial to create a small blog where I can…]]></description><link>https://ben-james-dodwell.github.io/gatsby-blog-for-github-pages/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ben-james-dodwell.github.io/gatsby-blog-for-github-pages/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 17:12:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have a personal project that I&apos;ve wanted to start for a while, and felt that it could be beneficial to create a small blog where I can capture some of my thoughts as it progresses. I will cover that project in the next post, but wanted to begin with some information about the setup of the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve opted to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; for hosting, primarily because it&apos;s simple and free. An added benefit is that it, of course, uses a GitHub repository for source control and GitHub Actions for a continuous deployment pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the content itself, I&apos;ve utilised &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt; and specifically the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/starters/gatsbyjs/gatsby-starter-blog&quot;&gt;gatsby-starter-blog&lt;/a&gt; template. I have some familiarity with Gatsby from a project last year, where I used it to create a quiz that I hosted with interactive media components. The framework provides some good quality of life features such as templating, and markdown to HTML conversion, without being overly complicated for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/docs/how-to/previews-deploys-hosting/how-gatsby-works-with-github-pages/&quot;&gt;gh-pages&lt;/a&gt; package which I have installed that allows me to create a deploy script that makes it easier to build and push the Gatsby site to GitHub Pages. I am using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ben-james-dodwell/github-pages-blog&quot;&gt;github-pages-blog&lt;/a&gt; repository for the source code of the Gatsby site, separate to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ben-james-dodwell/ben-james-dodwell.github.io&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; repository for the built static pages.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>