<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[A GitHub Pages Blog using Gatsby, covering personal projects relating to Software Development, DevOps, and Cloud Infrastructure.]]></description><link>https://ben-james-dodwell.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 18:22:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Blog for GitHub Pages]]></title><description><![CDATA[I have personal project that I've wanted to start for a while, and felt that it could be beneficial to start a small blog where I can…]]></description><link>https://ben-james-dodwell.github.io/gatsby-blog-for-github-pages/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ben-james-dodwell.github.io/gatsby-blog-for-github-pages/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 17:12:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have personal project that I&apos;ve wanted to start for a while, and felt that it could be beneficial to start a small blog where I can capture some of my thoughts. I will cover that project in the next post, but wanted to begin with some information about the setup of the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve opted to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; for hosting, primarily because it&apos;s simple and free. An added benefit is that it uses a GitHub repository for source control and GitHub Actions for a continuous deployment pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the content itself, I&apos;ve utilised &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt; and specifically the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/starters/gatsbyjs/gatsby-starter-blog&quot;&gt;gatsby-starter-blog&lt;/a&gt; template. I have some familiarity with Gatsby from a project last year, where I used it to create a quiz that I hosted with interactive media components. The framework provides some good quality of life features such as templating, and markdown to HTML conversion, without being overly complicated for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>